Guide to the Stanford University Commencement Collection SC1020
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University commencement collection
1892-2016
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University
SC1020
12.25 Linear Feet (19 boxes)
Addresses, programs, audio-visual recordings, and other materials documenting Stanford University commencement ceremonies
Information about Access
The materials are open for research.
Audio-visual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy.
Description of the Collection
The materials consist of addresses, programs, audio-visual recordings, and other materials documenting Stanford University commencement ceremonies.
Arrangement note
The materials are arranged in four series: Series 1. Addresses; Series 2. Programs; Series 3. Audio-Visual Recordings; Series 4. Additional Material.
Videorecordings.; Stanford University. Class of 1989; Zahir, Jazib.; Stanford University. Class of 1990; Schlenker, Robert G.; Gardner, John W. (John William); Sano, Roy I. (Roy Isao); Saperstein, David.; Kennedy, Donald; Qualls, Ralph A.; Rhea, Joseph.; Pinsky, Robert.; Purdy, Ralph S.; Jobs, Steve, 1955-2011; Mitchell, Thornton W.; Perry, William James; Lara-Braud, Jorge.; McLennan, Scotty.; Jemison, Mae C.; Stanford University. Class of 1991; Hurley, Melvin T.; Stanford University. Class of 1992; Edelman, Marian Wright.; Stanford University. Class of 1993; Hennessy, John L.; Stanford University. Class of 1994; Stanford University; Koppel, Ted; Casper, Gerhard; Stanford University. Class of 1995; Feinstein, Dianne; Stanford University. Class of 1996; Ellis, Wilma.; Stanford University. Class of 1997; Stanford University. Class of 1998; Stanford University. Class of 1999; Carter, Stephen L.; Stanford University. Class of 2000; Brokaw, Tom.; Stanford University. Class of 2005; Breyer, Stephen G.; Stanford University. Class of 2006; Boorstein, Sylvia.; Stone, William Edward.; Annan, Kofi A. (Kofi Atta); Trudeau, G. B.; Varnedoe, Kirk; Wynn, Prathaia Hall.
- Addresses, 1893-2012; Series 1
- Programs, 1892-2016; Series 2
  - 1st Annual Commencement, 1892 Jun 15 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 2nd Annual Commencement, 1893 May 31 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 3rd Annual Commencement, 1894 May 30 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 4th Annual Commencement, 1895 May 29 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 5th Annual Commencement, 1896 May 27 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 6th Annual Commencement, 1897 May 26 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 7th Annual Commencement, 1898 May 25 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 8th Annual Commencement, 1899 May 24 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 9th Annual Commencement, 1900 May 30 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 10th Annual Commencement, 1901 May 29 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - 11th Annual Commencement, 1902 May 28 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - 12th Annual Commencement, 1903 May 25 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 13th Annual Commencement, 1904 May 18 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 14th Annual Commencement, 1905 May 24 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 15th Annual Commencement, 1906 Sep 15 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 16th Annual Commencement, 1907 May 22 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - 17th Annual Commencement, 1908 May 20 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - 18th Annual Commencement, 1909 May 19 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - 19th Annual Commencement, 1910 May 23 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - 20th Annual Commencement, 1911 May 22 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - 21st Annual Commencement, 1912 May 20 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - 22nd Annual Commencement, 1913 May 19 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - 23rd Annual Commencement, 1914 May 18 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - 24th Annual Commencement, 1915 May 17 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - 25th Annual Commencement, 1916 May 22 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - 26th Annual Commencement, 1917 May 21 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - 27th Annual Commencement, 1918 Jun 17 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - 28th Annual Commencement, 1919 Jun 16 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - 29th Annual Commencement, 1920 Jun 21 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - 30th Annual Commencement, 1921 Jun 20 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - 31st Annual Commencement, 1922 Jun 19 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - 32nd Annual Commencement, 1923 Jun 18 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - 33rd Annual Commencement, 1924 Jun 23 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - 34th Annual Commencement, 1925 Jun 22 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - 35th Annual Commencement, 1926 Jun 21 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - 36th Annual Commencement, 1927 Jun 20 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - 37th Annual Commencement, 1928 Jun 18 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - 38th Annual Commencement, 1929 Jun 17 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - 39th Annual Commencement, 1930 Jun 16 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 40th Annual Commencement, 1931 Jun 15 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 41st Annual Commencement, 1932 Jun 20 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - 42nd Annual Commencement, 1933 Jun 19 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - 43rd Annual Commencement, 1934 Jun 18 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - 44th Annual Commencement, 1935 Jun 16 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - 45th Annual Commencement, 1936 Jun 14 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - 46th Annual Commencement, 1937 Jun 13 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - 47th Annual Commencement, 1938 Jun 19 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - 48th Annual Commencement, 1939 Jun 18 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - 49th Annual Commencement, 1940 Jun 16 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - 50th Annual Commencement, 1941 Jun 15 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - 51st Annual Commencement, 1942 Jun 14 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - 52nd Annual Commencement, 1943 Jun 13 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - 53rd Annual Commencement, 1944 Jul 2 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - 54th Annual Commencement, 1945 Jun 17 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - 55th Annual Commencement, 1946 Jun 16 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - 56th Annual Commencement, 1947 Jun 15 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - 57th Annual Commencement, 1948 Jun 13 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - 58th Annual Commencement, 1949 Jun 19 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - 59th Annual Commencement, 1950 Jun 18 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - 60th Annual Commencement, 1951 Jun 17 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - 61st Annual Commencement, 1952 Jun 15 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - 62nd Annual Commencement, 1953 Jun 14 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - 63rd Annual Commencement, 1954 Jun 13 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - 64th Annual Commencement, 1955 Jun 19 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - 65th Annual Commencement, 1956 Jun 17 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - 66th Annual Commencement, 1957 Jun 16 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - 67th Annual Commencement, 1958 Jun 15 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - 68th Annual Commencement, 1959 Jun 14 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - 69th Annual Commencement, 1960 Jun 12 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - 70th Annual Commencement, 1961 Jun 18 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - 71st Annual Commencement, 1962 Jun 17 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - 72nd Annual Commencement, 1963 Jun 19 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - 73rd Annual Commencement, 1964 Jun 14 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - 74th Annual Commencement, 1965 Jun 13 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - 75th Annual Commencement, 1966 Jun 12 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - 76th Annual Commencement, 1967 Jun 18 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - 77th Annual Commencement, 1968 Jun 16 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - 78th Annual Commencement, 1969 Jun 15 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - 79th Annual Commencement, 1970 Jun 14 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - 80th Annual Commencement, 1971 Jun 13 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - 81st Annual Commencement, 1972 Jun 11 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - 82nd Annual Commencement, 1973 Jun 17 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - 83rd Annual Commencement, 1974 Jun 16 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - 84th Annual Commencement, 1975 Jun 15 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - 85th Annual Commencement, 1976 Jun 13 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - 86th Annual Commencement, 1977 Jun 12 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - 87th Annual Commencement, 1978 Jun 18 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - 88th Annual Commencement, 1979 Jun 17 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - 89th Annual Commencement, 1980 Jun 15 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - 90th Annual Commencement, 1981 Jun 14 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - 91st Annual Commencement, 1982 Jun 13 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - 92nd Annual Commencement, 1983 Jun 12 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - 93rd Annual Commencement, 1984 Jun 17 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - 94th Annual Commencement, 1985 Jun 16 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - 95th Annual Commencement, 1986 Jun 15 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - 96th Annual Commencement, 1987 Jun 14 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - 97th Annual Commencement, 1988 Jun 12 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - 98th Annual Commencement, 1989 Jun 18 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - 99th Annual Commencement, 1990 Jun 17 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - 100th Annual Commencement, 1991 Jun 16 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - 101st Annual Commencement, 1992 Jun 14 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - 102nd Annual Commencement, 1993 Jun 13 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - 103rd Annual Commencement, 1994 Jun 12 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - 104th Annual Commencement, 1995 Jun 18 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - 105th Annual Commencement, 1996 Jun 16 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - 106th Annual Commencement, 1997 Jun 15 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - 107th Annual Commencement, 1998 Jun 14 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - 109th Annual Commencement, 2000 Jun 11 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - 110th Annual Commencement, 2001 Jun 17 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - 111th Annual Commencement, 2002 Jun 16 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - 112th Annual Commencement, 2003 Jun 15 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - 113th Annual Commencement, 2004 Jun 13 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - 114th Annual Commencement, 2005 Jun 12 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - 116th Annual Commencement, 2007 Jun 17 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - 117th Annual Commencement, 2008 Jun 15 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - 118th Annual Commencement, 2009 Jun 14 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - 119th Annual Commencement, 2010 Jun 13 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - 120th Annual Commencement, 2011 Jun 12 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - 121st Annual Commencement, 2012 Jun 14-17 (Box 13)
  - 122nd Annual Commencement, 2013 Jun 16; Accession ARCH.2014-064 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - 123rd Annual Commencement, 2014 Jun 15 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - 124th Annual Commencement, 2015-06-14 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - 64th-67th Annual Commencement (Bound), 1955-1958; 1 volume(s) (Box 11)
  - 68th-71st Annual Commencement (Bound), 1959-1962; 1 volume(s) (Box 11)
  - 72nd-75th Annual Commencement (Bound), 1963-1966; 1 volume(s) (Box 11)
  - 125th Annual Commencement, 2016 June 12 (Box 13)
- Audiovisual materials, 1937-2013; Series 3
  - 46th annual commencement and campus scenes, 1937; V250; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 2)
    Scope and Contents note
    VHS copy of 8mm film footage of the 1937 commencement in Frost Amphitheater and other campus scenes including Toyon and Branner Halls; persons on the tape include Mitchell, Melvin T. Hurley, Ralph Purdy, Ralph Qualls, Robert Schlenker, and Joseph Rhea.
    Biographical/Historical note
    Thornton W. Mitchell earned his A.B. in history at Stanford University in 1937.
    Stanford University -- Students.; Mitchell, Thornton W.; Purdy, Ralph S.; Qualls, Ralph A.; Rhea, Joseph.; Schlenker, Robert G.; Hurley, Melvin T.; Mitchell, Thornton W.
  - 86th annual commencement, 1977 Jun 12; 2 audiotape reel(s) (Box 2)
  - 88th annual commencement, 1979 (Box 3)
  - 89th annual commencement, 1980 (Box 3)
  - 90th annual commencement, 1981 Jun 14; 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 3)
  - 98th annual commencement, 1989; 2 videotape(s) (VHS)
    Video tape of the 1989 commencement activities. Includes the Baccalaureate service with speaker Jorge Lara-Braud, the class plaque ceremony, class day luncheon with talk by William Stone (president of the Stanford Alumni Association), commencement address by Garry Trudeau, and commencement remarks by Stanford University President Donald Kennedy.
    Stanford University -- Students.; Kennedy, Donald; Stone, William Edward.; Lara-Braud, Jorge.; Trudeau, G. B.
  - 99th annual commencement, 1990; 1 videotape(s) (vhs)
    Includes the Baccalaureate service with speaker Rabbi David Saperstein, the class plaque ceremony, class day luncheon with talk by William Stone and songs by the Fleet Street Singers, commencement address by Marion Wright Edelman, and commencement remarks by Stanford University President Donald Kennedy.
    Fleet Street Singers.; Saperstein, David.; Kennedy, Donald; Edelman, Marian Wright.; Stone, William Edward.; Stanford University. Class of 1990
  - 100th annual commencement, 1991 Jun 16; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 1)
  - 101st annual commencement, 1992; 2 videotape(s) (vhs)
    Baccalaureate service with speaker Rev. Prathaia Hall Wynn, the class plaque ceremony, class day luncheon highlights with the Band and Dollies, commencement address by Kirk Varnedoe, and commencement remarks by Stanford University President Donald Kennedy.
    Wynn, Prathaia Hall.; Varnedoe, Kirk; Stanford University. Class of 1992; Kennedy, Donald
    - Part 1 protection master (dub of 1" edited master), 1992; 1478; 1 videotape(s) (mii) (Box 3)
  - 102nd annual commencement, 1993; film reel (35mm); 1 optical disc(s) (DVD) (Box not specified)
    Includes the Baccalaureate service with speaker Bishop Roy I. Sano, the class plaque ceremony, class day luncheon highlights, commencement address by Dianne Feinstein, and commencement remarks by Stanford University President Gerhard Casper.
    Feinstein, Dianne; Stanford University. Class of 1993; Casper, Gerhard; Sano, Roy I. (Roy Isao)
  - 103rd annual commencement, 1994 Jun 12; 1 optical disc(s) (DVD)
    Includes the Baccalaureate service with speaker Bishop Wilma Ellis, the class plaque ceremony, class day luncheon highlights with the Fleet Street Singers, commencement address by Stephen Carter, and commencement remarks by Stanford University President Gerhard Casper.
    Stanford University. Class of 1994; Ellis, Wilma.; Casper, Gerhard; Carter, Stephen L.
    - Commencement Address: Stephen Carter, 1994; 2026; 1 videotape reel(s) (Box 4)
    - Stanford Commencement with highlights of Baccaluareate Service and Senior Class Day Luncheon, 1994; 2044; 1 videotape reel(s) (Box 4)
  - 104th annual commencement, 1995 Jun 19; 1 optical disc(s) (DVD)
    Includes commencement address by William Perry and commencement remarks by Stanford University President Gerhard Casper.
    Casper, Gerhard; Perry, William James
    - 1995 Commencement, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 3)
  - 105th annual commencement, 1996; 2 videotape(s) (betacam-sp l) (Box 3)
    Includes commencement address by Mae Jemison and commencement remarks by Stanford University President Gerhard Casper.
    Jemison, Mae C.; Casper, Gerhard
    - Use Copy, 1996; 1 optical disc(s) (dvd)
    - Backup copy, 1996; 1 videotape(s) (betacam-sp l) (Box 1)
    - Stanford Presents Stanford Commencement, Part I, 1996; 1 videotape(s) (betacam-sp) (Box 3)
    - Stanford Presents Stanford Commencement, Part II, 1996; 1 videotape(s) (betacam-sp) (Box 3)
    - 105th Commencement, 1996; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 3)
  - 106th annual commencement, 1997; 2 videotape(s) (betacam-sp l) (Box 3)
    Includes commencement address by Stephen Breyer and commencement remarks by Stanford University President Gerhard Casper.
    Casper, Gerhard; Breyer, Stephen G.
    - Stanford Presents the 106th Annual Commencement, Tape A, 1997; 1 videotape(s) (betacam-sp) (Box 3)
    - Stanford Presents the 106th Annual Commencement, Tape B, 1997; 1 videotape(s) (betacam-sp) (Box 3)
    - 106th Commencement, 1997; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 3)
  - 107th annual commencement, 1998; 2 videotape(s) (betacam-sp l) (Box 1)
    Includes commencement address by Ted Koppel and commencement remarks by Stanford University President Gerhard Casper.
    Casper, Gerhard; Koppel, Ted
    - Stanford Presents "107th Commencement Ceremonies," Tape 1, 1998; 1 videotape(s) (betacam-sp) (Box 3)
    - Stanford Presents "107th Commencement Ceremonies," Tape 2, 1998; 1 videotape(s) (betacam-sp) (Box 3)
    - 'Walky Walk' & 'America the Beautiful,' Tape 1 of 4, 1998 Jun 14; 1 videotape(s) (betacam-sp) (Box 3)
    - Casper; Start of Ted Koppel Speech, Tape 2 of 4, 1998 Jun 14; 1 videotape(s) (betacam-sp) (Box 3)
    - Koppel ends; awards/presentations, Tape 3 of 4, 1998 Jun 14; 1 videotape(s) (betacam-sp) (Box 3)
    - Awards; Casper end speech; recessional/hugs & band, Tape 4 of 4, 1998 Jun 14; 1 videotape(s) (betacam-sp) (Box 3)
    - 107th Commencement, 1998; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 3)
  - 108th annual commencement, 1999 Jun 13; 2 videotape(s) (betacam-sp l); 1 optical disc(s) (DVD) (Box 1)
    Includes commencement address by Robert Pinsky and commencement remarks by Stanford University President Gerhard Casper.
    Pinsky, Robert.; Casper, Gerhard
    - Stanford Presents 1999 Commencement Ceremonies (Pinsky), Part 1, 1 videotape(s) (betacam-sp) (Box 3)
    - Stanford Presents 1999 Commencement Ceremonies (Pinsky), Part 2, 1 videotape(s) (betacam-sp) (Box 3)
    - Stanford Presents: 1999 Commencement Ceremonies, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 3)
    - 1999 Commencement, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 3)
    - Commencement, 1999; 99-0613-1; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 3)
      Scope and Contents
      Graduation 1999, "Play only". Departing Provost Condoleezza Rice was a speaker.
  - 109th annual commencement, 2000 Jun 11; 1 videotape(s) (betacam-sp l); 1 optical disc(s) (DVD) (Box 1)
    Includes commencement address by Kofi Annan and commencement remarks by Stanford University President Gerhard Casper.
    Annan, Kofi A. (Kofi Atta); Casper, Gerhard
    - Stanford Presents 2000 Commencement, 1 videotape(s) (betacam-sp) (Box 3)
    - Graduation/Commencement, 2000 Jun 11; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 3)
    - 109th Commencement (copy 2), 2000; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 3)
  - 110th annual commencement, 2001
    - Stanford Presents the 110th Annual Commencement, 2001; 1 videotape(s) (betacam-sp l) (Box 3)
    - Stanford Presents the 110th Commencement at Stanford (Fiorina), 2001; 1 videotape(s) (betacam-sp l) (Box 3)
    - Stanford Commencement, 2001 Jun 17; 1 videotape(s) (betacam-sp) (Box 3)
    - 2001 Commencement, Bill and Hillary Clinton, 01-0617-1; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 3)
      Scenes from the 2001 commencement, Former President Bill Clinton and Secretary of State, Hillary Clinton, were in attendance. Chelsea Clinton graduated. Carleton (Carly) S. Fiorina was the commencement speaker. Clock Tower audio; Campus Views; Bill and Hillary Clinton in the stands 18:03; Graduates 24:31; Chelsea,Hillary and Bill 28:12
    - 110th Commencement, Carly Fiorina, 2001 Jun 17; 01-0617-2a; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 3)
      110th Commencement, Carleton (Carly) S. Fiorina, chief executive officer of Hewlett-Packard, delivers the Commencement address.
    - 110th Commencement, Carly Fiorina, 2001 Jun 17; 01-0617-2b; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 3)
    - 110th Commencement, Carly Fiorina, 2001 Jun 17; 01-0617-2c; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 3)
    - Commencement, Clinton Photo-op, 2001; 01-0617-3; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 3)
      2001 commencement, Carleton (Carly) S. Fiorina was the commencement speaker. Former President Bill Clinton and Secretary of State, Hillary Clinton, were in attendance. Chelsea Clinton graduated. Bill Clinton Photo-op.
    - Commencement, Clintons, 2001; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 3)
  - 111th annual commencement, 2002 Jun 16
    - Wacky Walk, 2002 Jun 16; 3 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 1)
    - Dinkelspiel and Gores Awards, 2002 Jun; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 1)
    - Ceremony, 2002 Jun 16; 1 videotape(s) (dvcam) (Box 1)
    - 111th Commencement (Damon #1), 2002; 02-0616-1a; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 3)
      U.S. National Security Adviser and former university Provost Condoleezza Rice spoke at Stanford's 111th Commencement on June 16. Field Tape shot list: Close up of Rice and Hennessy :30:00; America the beautiful song 2:02:00; Speech begins 9:36:00
    - 111th Commencement (Damon #2), 2002 Jun 16; 02-0616-1b; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 3)
      U.S. National Security Adviser and former university Provost Condoleezza Rice spoke at Stanford's 111th Commencement on June 16. choir sings 2:10; Damon 3:30
    - Commencement, 2002 Jun 16; 02-0616-2; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 3)
      Opens with a prayer from Stanford Church Offical Hennessy give the class stats. U.S. National Security Adviser and former university Provost Condoleezza Rice spoke at Stanford's 111th Commencement on June 16.
    - Wacky Walk 2002, Commencement, Condoleezza Rice, 2002 Jun 16; 02-0616-3; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 3)
      WEB DESCRIPTION Graduates engage in the Wacky Walk--a now traditional 30 minutes of performance art by graduates entering the stadium--which precedes the official ceremonies. Field tape shot list: Crowd Shots; Student Playing; Stanford Flag waving :30:00; Pillow fight 1:19; Bubbles 2:00; Paper dominos 3:00; Flower hats 4:10; Human Basketball hoop 5:00; Purple wigs 6:00; Beer Keg Drummers 6:10; Wacky Walk 7:00; Jump rope 8:15; Glitter wigs and dresses 9:50; Faculty walks in 10:00; Condoleezza Rice 13:40; Gerhard Casper 15:20; Condoleezza Rice takes the stage 16:10; Camera 2 has a better view of Condoleezza Rice. [Tape is labeled as: Townsend, Condi Reel TRT: 1:21, 48:00, 54:00, 1:00, 15:00, Hugs]
  - 112th annual commencement, 2003 Jun 15
    - Wacky Walk, 2003 Jun 15; 3 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 1)
    - Wacky Walk, 2003 Jun 15; 1 videotape(s) (betacam-sp) (Box 1)
    - Address, 2003 Jun 15; 2 videotape(s) (betacam-sp l) (Box 1)
    - Commencement, 2003 Jun 15; 03-0615-2a; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 3)
      Stanford's 112th Commencement, at which 1,865 bachelor's degrees, 1,976 master's degrees and 899 doctoral degrees were awarded.
    - Commencement, 2003 Jun 15; 03-0615-2b; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 3)
  - 113th annual commencement, 2004 Jun 13
    - Stanford Band, 2004; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 1)
    - B-Roll, 2004 Jun 13; 1 videotape(s) (betacam-sp) (Box 1)
    - Commencement, 1 videotape(s) (betacam-sp l) (Box 1)
    - Commencement, 2 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 1)
    - Commencement, Justic Sandra Day O'Connor, 2004 Jun 13; 04-613-1; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 1)
      U.S. Supreme Court Justice Sandra Day O'Connor spoke to graduating students at the 113th Commencement Ceremony on June 13, telling them that "our nation needs bridges, and bridges are built by those who look to the future and dedicate themselves to helping others.
    - Commencement, 1 videotape(s) (dvcam) (Box 1)
  - 114th annual commencement, 2005 Jun 12; 1 videotape(s) (betacam-sp l)
    Zahir, Jazib.; Jobs, Steve, 1955-2011; Hennessy, John L.; Boorstein, Sylvia.; Stanford University. Class of 2005; McLennan, Scotty.
    - Use Copy, 1 optical disc(s) (DVD)
    - Wacky Walk, 2005 Jun 12; 2 videotape(s) (betacam-sp l) (Box 1)
    - Preview-Ceremony, 2005 Jun 12; 1 videotape(s) (betacam-sp l) (Box 1)
    - Address, 2005 Jun 12; 1 videotape(s) (betacam-sp l) (Box 1)
    - Ceremony, 4 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 1)
  - 115th annual commencement, 2006; 1 videotape(s) (betacam-sp l); 1 optical disc(s) (DVD)
    Includes commencement address by Tom Brokaw and commencement remarks by Stanford University President John Hennessy.
    Brokaw, Tom.; Stanford University. Class of 2006; Hennessy, John L.
    - Grad Commencement, Gregorian, 2006; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 3)
    - Grad Commencement, Gregorian, Cutaways, 2006; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 3)
    - Grad Commencement PGM REC SD, 2006; 2 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 3)
    - Undergrad Commence Brokaw, 2006; 2 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 3)
    - Undergrad Commence Wacky Walk Cutaways, 2006; 2 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 3)
    - Undergrad Commence Brokaw Podium, 2006; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 3)
    - Undergrad Commence Brokaw Podium, 2006; 06-0618-3b; 1 videotape(s) (minidv hdv) (Box 5)
  - 116th annual commencement, 2007 Jun 17
    - Commencement Wacky Walk/Cutaway Gioia Speech, 2007 Jun 17; 07-0617-1; 1 videotape(s) (minidv hdv) (Box 3)
      2007 Commencement at the Stanford Stadium. It contains the students' wacky walk. Tape also contains commencement speech by Poet Dana Gioia.
  - 117th annual commencement, 2008 Jun 15; 2 videotape(s) (minidv hdv)
    - Onstage Pre-Oprah, 2008-06-15; 08-0615-1a (Box 5)
    - #3: Kirby Bumpus, 2008-06-15; 08-0615-2a (Box 5)
    - Commencement, 2008-06-15; 08-0615-3a (Box 5)
    - Commencement, 2008-06-15; 08-0615-3b (Box 5)
    - A Oprah Arrives, Wacky Walk, Oprah Cutaways, 2008-06-15; 08-0615-4 (Box 5)
  - 119th annual commencement, 2010-06-13
    - Wacky Walk, 2010-06-13; 10-0613-1 (Box 5)